{
  "name": "PA179 - exam",
  "note": "Záverečná zkouška z PA179 ‑ ověřené správné odpovědi (opravená zkouška)",
  "chips": ["exam"],
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Choose true statements about Project",
      "correct": [
        "Project contains repeatable processes",
        "Project delivers a unique product or service"
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "A Project is repeatable",
        "Project is best visualized with BPD"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following characteristics discourage from using PRINCE2 standard?",
      "correct": ["Research type of project, unclear scope"],
      "wrong": [
        "Junior project manager",
        "Critical infrastructure delivery",
        "Hierarchic organizational structure, large teams in different locations"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following combinations is suitable for large projects (one year or more)?",
      "correct": ["UP and IPMA ICB", "UP and PM BOK", "UP and PRINCE2"],
      "wrong": ["UP and Scrum"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which consequences may result from adding an item to Product Backlog (in a project according to Scrum)?",
      "correct": [
        "Other item may not be developed",
        "Risk register may change"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Contract has to be changed", "Current Sprint may be stopped"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the outcome of Sprint Retrospective?",
      "correct": ["Identification of one process improvement"],
      "wrong": [
        "Next stage plan",
        "Updating Sprint Backlog",
        "Updating Sprint Retrospectlog"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following knowledge areas in PMBOK is focusing on definition of sequence of project activities?",
      "correct": ["Schedule"],
      "wrong": ["Plan", "Integration", "Scope"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following UML diagrams is suitable for capturing requirements?",
      "correct": ["Use Case Diagram"],
      "wrong": ["Requirements Diagram", "Sequence Diagram", "User Story"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is responsible for Product Backlog?",
      "correct": ["Product Owner"],
      "wrong": ["Scrum Master", "Product Master", "Team of developers"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following combinations is suitable for projects with complex and unpredictable scope?",
      "correct": ["Scrum and IPMA ICB"],
      "wrong": ["Scrum and PRINCE2", "UP and IPMA ICB", "UP and PRINCE2"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following options belong to 'People Competencies' according to IPMA ICB?",
      "correct": [
        "Negotiation, Self-reflection and Self-management, Teamwork",
        "Personal communication, Conflict and Crisis, Resourcefulness",
        "Leadership, Relations and Engagement, Results Orientation"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Proactivity, Time Management, Responsibility"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What can be read from Burndown chart?",
      "correct": [
        "Remaining work until end of sprint",
        "Team is falling behind a plan"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Remaining project days", "Remaining to-do items for today"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following techniques/tools are using man-day or man-month units?",
      "correct": ["PERT"],
      "wrong": ["Gantt chart", "Planning poker", "Burndown chart"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following concepts contains set of projects?",
      "correct": ["Portfolio", "Program"],
      "wrong": ["Process", "Project"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are Scrum Artifacts (as per Scrum)?",
      "correct": ["Product Increment", "Product Backlog", "Sprint Backlog"],
      "wrong": ["Story Point"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements are true (according to UP)?",
      "correct": [
        "An iteration should not be longer than 3 months",
        "A difference between two consecutive iterations is called increment",
        "An iteration is like a mini project"
      ],
      "wrong": ["A sum of two consecutive iterations is called increment"]
    }
  ]
}
